Flat 2, Canfield House, Finchley Road London 07414988908 rmacg89@gmail.com www.github.com/ryanmacg

Ryan MacGillivray

Summary

Description

Hi, I'm Ryan! I've spent since 2011 working, with Ruby, Ruby on Rails and the Rails stack in general. I like to poke at things and see how they work, give talks on things I know nothing about so I have to learn about them and make coffee in an obsessive manner.

When I'm not playing with Go, Swift or Ruby I sometimes make beer which I then feed to my coworkers or arrange beer and bad movie nights in the office.

Computer Skills

Languages:

Fluent: Ruby, Ruby on Rails

Working Knowledge: JavaScript, Coffeescript, jQuery, Go, Python

Experience

2015 – Present Developer, Currency Cloud, London.

Working on FinTech platform comprising of JRuby, Sinatra and Rails applications

Responsible for helping more junior team members with issues
Maintaining existing platform functionality as well as extending it
Migration of Sinatra application off of HornetQ to RabbitMQ

Migration of Sinatra application off of Torquebox to modern application server

Development of front end features using Bootstrap and Knockout.JS

2013 - 2015

Ruby On Rails Developer, tictoc family, Glasgow.

Lead developer on several larger client sites including SCO, B-Eat and GAP Group

Lead developer on an as yet unreleased product:

- Developed admin backend for product
- Converted several costly actions to background jobs using ActiveJob, Sidekiq and the Services pattern
- Established standard JSON format for several disparate APIs
- Developed initial prototype and client facing implementation of project

Led move from headless git server to self hosted GitLab.

Contributed to proprietary Rails 4 based CMS for use in client projects.

2011 - 2013

IT Support Technician, JTC Furniture Group, Dundee.

Led development on two internal Ruby on Rails (3.2) based tools that have since been open sourced.

Education

2007 - 2011

Computing, University of Abertay, Dundee, Bachelor of Science.

Extra

Maintainer of Glub gem - see https://github.com/ryanmacg/glub

Built Kerstman secret santa matcher -

see https://github.com/ryanmacg/kerstman and https://kerstman.herokuapp.com/

Built UKIP Soundbite Generator Toy -

see https://github.com/ryanmacg/ukip-butts and http://ukip.butts.rip/

Delivered lightning talk at Scottish Ruby Users Group on Postgres Arrays in Rails 4 -

see https://www.haikudeck.com/p/DJFtjsL98H/database-fuckery